Littauer Library Collection of Miscellaneous Union Files 5964
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Littauer Library Collection of Miscellaneous Union Files
1936-1970
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Harvard University Library
5964
35.61 cubic feet
35.6 linear ft.
Records (documents).
5743733
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1
Harvard University.; Harvard University. Littauer Library; National Maritime Union of America
5743733
- National Maritime Union. Files, 1930s-1940s. (Box 1)
  - Address of Joseph Curran, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Misc. papers
  - 13 1936 Rank and File Leaflets (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History of Marine Transportation, 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 24 Triple Punch - Publication of T.E.L. Oriente, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Article and book
  - 31 1941 Convention - Cleveland (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Misc. papers and 2 books
  - 31 1941 Convention - Cleveland (cont.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 43 Memoranda, CIO Maritime Committee to House Committee on Interstate Migration - Eleanor Kahn, 1935-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 46 Two Years, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Magazine
  - 47 Lease - Lend, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 48 Pan American Seaman's Organization (Eddie Gordon), 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 49 NMU and War, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 57 NMU and Discrimination, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 60 Curran - Anti War - Peace Speeches, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 61 NMU and World War II, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 70 Precious Documents, 1918-1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 70 Precious Documents Continued, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 50 Hanson Baldwin Episode - Oct 1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 159 Seamen in the War, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Misc. papers and booklet
  - 62 Robinson Speech British Shipping and the War, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 63 Shipping Scandals in World War II, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 64 Ship Owner Lobby - "Pressure Boys", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 69 NMU Post War, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 77 Historical, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 65 Standard, W - British Influence in U.S. Merchant Marine, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 79 Ship-owner Profit, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 101 Curran Reports to National Council, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 103 Nazi Cells, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 105 Curran Profile - Boyer, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 104 Allan Barnard "Operation Plunder", 1946 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 112 Ship Owner Conniving and Federal Funds - Depredations, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 113 Lewis Article for Journal of Commerce (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 116 National Council, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 162 Seamen and Spain, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 167 ARTA Disruption, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 165 Letter to Hull July of 1937 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - 164 Filipino Issue (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 119 Scandinavian Seamen, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 124 Bland on Merchant Marine, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Booklet
  - 126 NMU Organizational Chart (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Chart
  - Constitutions NMU 1937 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- National Maritime Union. Files, 1930's-1940's. (Box 2)
  - 146 BMI Hearings, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    2 books
  - 154 Roper Report - Bureau of Marine Inspection and Navigation, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - War Risk Insurance and Compensation, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 110 Bureau of Marine Inspection and Navigation - C.D. Mallory, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 152 Bureau of Marine Inspection and Navigation, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Booklets and Misc. papers
  - 90 Tanker Strike, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 30 Tanker Strike - Late Thirties, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 85 Dirksen Bill - Exhibits List and Memo Draft and Outline, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Book and Misc. papers
  - 15 William L. Standard, 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Misc. papers and Article
  - 4 Curran Testimony, Dirksen Bill (HR 2662 1939) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 76 Other Legislation, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Answering Legislative Attacks, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 56 Unity Movements East and West Coast, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 84 Unity Leaflet, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - West Coast Pamphlets, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - West Coast Pamphlets Continued, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Pamphlets and Book
  - 19 Marine Cooks and Stewards, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 172 The Pilot - Bridges, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 117 West Coast, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 80 Owens Affidavits (MFOW frauds), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 125 Harry Bridges, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 121 King - Connor - Ramsey, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 120 SUP (Sailors' Union of the Pacific), 1936 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 109 Ferguson Case, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Bridges Trials etc., 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 122 West Coast Strike 1936,1937 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 161 Misc. Leaflets, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Leaflets
  - Current Anti-Labor Activities - D.J. Saposs, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Box 2 Last Folder, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- National Maritime Union. Files, 1930's-1940's. (Box 3)
  - International Seaman's Union, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Modesto Trial and Songs, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Misc. papers and song lyrics
  - 178 Seaman's Journal Fall Strike 1936 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Manila Folder with Journal
  - Port Light Vol I through 1-42 1940 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Communists and NMU, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 169 Cadets Diary on Life at Sea (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 71 Howard Cullman Reports "Safety at Sea" Agitation, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Safety at Sea" Addresses, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 123 "Seamen Under the Red Flag", 1935 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 68 Code Hearings, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 3 WRC Bulletin Waterfront Research Committee 1938-40, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 20 "Hours, Wages, and Working Conditions in Domestic Water Transportation", 1936 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Originals too large to copy.
  - 53 Fall 1936 Strike Minutes (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 107 Wages and Working Conditions, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 89 Resolution Terminating Fall Strike, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 6 Affidavit of Rank and File Against ISU Leadership Nov. 1936 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 100 Striking ISU Members Correspondence, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Early Leaflets (Box 3, Folder 18)
    1937
  - 28 NMU Reports, On the Operations of the King-Carney Ship owner Group, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 51 Gulf and "Rank and File" Pilots, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Newspapers
  - 173 Gulf Pilots to Revolt, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 179 Gulf Labor Spies, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 54 Gulf Revolt 1939 - Tanker Strike S.S. Daylight Minutes (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 99 CIO Maritime Committee Report Oct. 1938 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 21 Report on Maritime Commission by Attorney General's Committee on Administrative Procedure, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Booklet and book
  - 97 Seamen and Maritime Commission, 1938-1941 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 58 Hoover Wreck and Black Falcon, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 18 Hoover Wreck Paper of Commerce State, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- National Maritime Union. Files, 1930's-1940's. (Box 4)
  - 9 Isthmian and Calmar Labor Board Cases, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 111 S.S. Texan, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 108 S.S. Malay "Mutiny", 1939 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Booklets
  - 129 Waterman Case, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 166 Bailey, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 55 FBI and NMU, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 171 Red Herring and Marine WRC (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Joseph Curran, National Maritime Union, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 168 McFadden on Merchant Marine, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Article
  - 102 McQuistion, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 86 Memo on World Telegram Forgeries, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 66 Eddie Levinson - Anti NMU, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Folder with misc. papers
  - 36 McFee Newspaper Columns, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 27 Anti NMU Material, 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Misc. articles
  - 158 Captain X, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 11 Early ISU Pilots (1935 Rank and File) Mimeographed. Starts with Volume 1, No. 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Misc. papers, articles, and folders
  - 157 Civil Liberties, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 78 Curran Personal, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 156 Curran for Congress, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Standard on Postwar Ship owner Conniving, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee Hearing, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Two books
  - Merchant Seamen and The Law, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Three booklets
  - Maritime Labor Board, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Book
  - MLB, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Report and two books
  - 16 Collective Bargaining in Marine, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Booklet and papers
  - 82 Taft on Maritime Labor Relations (see Magazine), 1941 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Misc. papers and magazine
  - Misc. Strike Papers Fall 1936 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Misc. papers and articles
  - 75 Maritime Legislation, 1937-1940 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- National Maritime Union. Files, 1930's-1940's. (Box 5)
  - 45 "The Right of Seamen to Strike" IJA, 1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 23 Legal Implications of Strike by Seamen - V.H. Rothchild, Yale Law Journal, May 1936, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Journal, booklet, misc. papers
  - Transportation Panama Canal, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 38 Analysis of Maritime Laws, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 161 Miscellaneous Leaflets Early NMU, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 170 Penalties for Misconduct (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 118 NMU Contracts, 1938-1941 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Misc. papers and booklets
  - 155 Early Days of NMU, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 32 Minutes - 1937 District Committee (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Envelope with misc. papers
  - First NMU Convention 1937 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Booklet, book, and folder with misc. papers
  - 160 NLRB, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - NMU Magazine, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Magazine and misc. papers
  - 182 Unity Leaflets, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Joe Ryan Prosecution, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 163 Longshoremen, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Newspaper articles
  - 81 Letter to Valentine on Police and ILA, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 74 N.Y. ILA Rank and File Court Action, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 114 Maritime Council, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 115 Harbor Workers (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 39 The Algic Case, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - NMU King Trial in the Pilot, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Labor Spies in NMU, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Booklet and article
  - 180 King Trial Pilots, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 177 Labor Spies Leaflets (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 176 Loones Confession "Rank and File" Pilot, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 175 "Rank and File" Pilot - Labor Spies, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Misc. newspapers
  - 174 Red and Black Ballot (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Ballots
  - 181 Carney Confession, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 83 Ashton Earle Letter Oct. 1937 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - 73 "We Accuse", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 35 New Orleans Convention - Resolution on Phonies 1939 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Booklets and Articles
  - 5 New Orleans Minutes, On "Gulf Situation", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 14 Transcript King Trial (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 17 Baseball Bat Raid, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence - Joint Strike Committee, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Joint Maritime Strike Committee Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Striking Members of the ISU Correspondence, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- National Maritime Union. Files, 1930's-1940's. (Box 6)
  - West Coast Sailors, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Gulf Ports Correspondence, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Strike Strategy Committee Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Philadelphia Waterfront District Council Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Misc. Papers
  - Revision of Copeland Act, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - NMU Application for Membership, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Atlantic and Gulf Port Strike Committee, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Striking ISU Members, Boston, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - New York Maritime Council Minutes and Correspondence, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letters of Reference, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Booklet and misc. papers
  - NMU Membership and Deposits, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Tanker Strike Fund, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Strike Bulletins, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Minutes and Legal Correspondence, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - NMU Finance Correspondence, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Membership, Deposits, Donations, and Receipts, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Strike Records and Member Details, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, Book Detail, and Brother Correspondence, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Minutes and Letters of Inquiry, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - The Pilot Publication Correspondence, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Thomas McGowan and Various Correspondence, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - NMU Membership - Application and Standing, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - George A Young and Other Brothers, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Fiscina, Young, Hearn, and McGowan Correspondence, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Letters Concerning Brother Membership and Status, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Brother Correspondence and Retiring Letter, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1937-38, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Organizations, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Committee Business Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Hearn and Jones Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Liberman, Byne, Degress, O'Connor, and Others, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- National Maritime Union. Finance Records. (Box 7)
  - Cases and Trials Concerning Members, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Receipts, Trials, and Notices, 1936-1939 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Concerning Particular Members, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Concerning Enclosed Documents and Dues, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - McGowan and Others - Various Letters, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Concerning Case and Strike Information, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Advisory to Ship's Delegate and Correspondence to Members - McGowan, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Boston Branch Correspondence, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Transfer of Books and Boston Branch Cont., 1940 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Boston Branch - Dickman, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 15 "Dispatcher", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Misc. papers and Book
  - 16 Day Book D-999, 1931-1937 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 17 Day Book D-999 and NMU Income/Expenditures, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 18 Dues Receipt Book, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 19 Advance Duplicate Petty Cash Receipt Book (no. 98), 1937 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Book and Receipt
  - 20 Deck Dec. 10, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 21 Record, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 22 Standard B + P Money Receipts (no. 5154), 1937 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Receipt and Book
  - 23 Journal J-999, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Journal
  - 24 National Order Book 1597, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Book and misc. papers
  - 25 NMU April-May 1938 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - 26 B-6, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - 27 Gibson's Challenge Triplicating Receipts, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - 28 Income/Expense Book, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- National Maritime Union. Finance Records. (Box 8)
  - 1937 Checkbook and Receipt Book (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1937 Receipt Books (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1937 Engine Receipt Book - August, September (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1937 Engine Receipt Books - September, October (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1937 Engine Receipt Books - November, December (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1937 Deck Receipt Books - August (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1937 Deck Receipt Books - September, October (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1937 Deck and Steward Receipt Books (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1937 Steward Receipt Books - October-December (Box 8, Folder 9)
    3 books
  - 1 1938 Checkbooks (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 2 1938 Checkbooks (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 3 1938 Checkbooks (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 4 1938 Checkbooks (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 1938 Receipt Book - January, February (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 1938 Receipt Books - March-May (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 1938 Receipt Books - April-June (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - 1 1938 Receipt Books (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - 2 1938 Receipt Books (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Receipt Book and Loose Receipts, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    1 book, 1 envelope
  - Payment Vouchers and Receipts, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    2 booklets and misc. receipts
  - Receipts and Money Orders, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- National Maritime Union. Papers. (Box 9)
  - 8 Paddy (Patrick) Whalen Case, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 22 Curran's Report to the Sixth National Convention, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - NMU Post War, 1944-1947 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Memo on Compulsory Arbitration, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Racketeering in Merchant Marine, 1916-1937 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - International Merchant Marine Control and Destruction of U.S. Lines (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The Fight, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Outline - mail subsidies, Black Committee, Merchant Marine Act 1932 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Book "International Seamen's Union of America, A Study of Its History and Problems", 1923 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography of Bibliographies, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    ILR has copies
  - Correspondence - Boston Branch NMU, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Fragile documents too extensive to copy
  - Thesis, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Original fragile, too extensive to copy
  - 1 Financial Receipts, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Misc. receipts
  - 2 Financial Receipts, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 3 Financial Receipts, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Envelope with misc. receipts
- National Maritime Union. Boston Local, Deep Ship Includes minutes, ballots regarding Coal Boat Agreement, strike materials, miscellaneous papers (Box 10)
  - Seaman's Union Picket Cards and Correspondence, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Misc. papers, booklets, cards
  - NMU Duplicates, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Envelope
  - Strike Material - Minutes, memos, etc., 1936-1937 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Large envelope
  - Minutes 1938 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Pledge Sheets and Miscellaneous, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Minutes - Morning Session, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Minutes - Afternoon Session, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Minutes - Baltimore and Providence, 1936-1937 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Misc. paper
  - Minutes - Florida and Gulf Ports, 1936-1937 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Minutes - West Coast and Other, 1936-1937 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Financial Records - October thru December 1938 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Ledger
  - Financial Records - January thru March 1939 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Financial Records - October thru December 1939 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Financial Records - August 1940 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Financial Records - July thru 1939 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Financial Records - April thru June 1939 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Financial Records - April thru June 1940 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Financial Records - January thru March 1940 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Financial Records - June thru August 1940 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Financial Records - July thru December 1940 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Minutes of New York Branch - 1937 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- National Maritime Union. Boston Local, Deep Ship Includes minutes, ballots regarding Coal Boat Agreement, strike materials, miscellaneous papers (Box 11)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Record of Union Book Member (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Port Ballots on Coal Boat, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Membership Records - Notebook, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Notebook
  - Minutes Membership Meetings, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Minutes Committee Meetings, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - EXG Sailors' Minutes, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Port Ballots 1938 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Shipping Cards, Report Sheets, etc., 1938 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Tanker Strike Cards, etc., 1939 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Cards and misc. papers
  - Striker Returns 36-37, 1936-1937 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Voting Records, etc., 1938 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Financial Records from Strike Committee, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Journal with misc. papers
  - Boston Strike Committee Miscellaneous, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Misc. books, papers
- Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators and Paperhangers of America. Glaziers Union Local 1044, Boston. 1930's-1940's. Includes receipt books, ballot cards, official paper ballots, completed membership application forms, financial records and miscellaneous co (Box 12)
  - Angelton Letter, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Folder
  - Letters, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Election Ballots, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Print Money, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Application for Membership, 1930-1942 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Glaziers Local Union Finances, 1936-1941 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Misc. envelopes
  - Glaziers Local Union Finances (1937-1938) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 2 Glaziers Local Union Finances (1937-1938) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Glaziers Local Union Finances and Cards, 1917-1936 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Misc. envelopes and cards
  - Checkbooks (1936-1938) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Misc. checkbooks
  - Miscellaneous Records - Finances, Phone Numbers, 1936-1938 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    6 books
  - Financial Expenses and Receipts, 1931-1940 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Receipts and Payments (1926-1927) (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Wander, Paul. Notes on Trade Union Policies (Box 13)
  - Glaziers Local Union Ballots - 1940 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Misc. ballots
  - Glaziers Local Union Ballots - 1941,1942 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Employment and Work Agreement - Records, 1924-1925 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Attendance, Elections, Debate - Records, 1924-1926 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Company Correspondence - Records, 1925-1926 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Education and Health Suggestions - Records, 1925-1926 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Function of Committees, Employees - Records, 1922-1926 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Welfare, Jurisdiction, Overtime - Records, 1924-1925 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Checkbooks, Receipts, 1936-1938 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    6 checkbooks and misc. receipts
  - Miscellaneous Checks and Receipts, 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Checks and Receipts Continued, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Paul Wander, Notes on Trade Union Policies, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- King, Carol. (Labor Lawyer, New York City) Collection. Includes briefs, correspondence, and related documents. 1930's. (Box 14)
  - Paul Wander's Notes, 1915-1922 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Picketing - Non Labor Disputes, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Police Violence, 1937-1938 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Public Contracts (Penna) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Sit Down Strikes, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Booklets and misc. papers
  - Yellow Dog Contracts, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Picketing - Mass., 1935-1938 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Picketing - New York, 1934-1936 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Misc. books, folders, and papers
  - Injunctions - Against Police, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Injunctions - Lewiston, Maine Strike (Shoe), 1937 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Misc. booklet, folder, and papers
  - Picketing - General, 1933-1938 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Kentucky Miners Case, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Picketing - Anti Picketing Ordinances, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Picketing - Anti Picketing Ordinance California, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 14)